{"lang": "en", "source": "tass", "title": "Iran won’t go to war with US — IRGC commander’s advisor", "link": "https://tass.com/world/1855175", "tags": ["World", "Middle East conflict"], "flavor": "art", "published": "Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:43:34 +0300", "published_parsed": [2024, 10, 11, 13, 43, 34, 4, 285, 0], "summary": "\"A war on Iran is inadmissible and we reassure the Iranian people that the Islamic republic’s armed forces are strong and are keeping an ear to the ground,\" General Hossein Daghighi said", "media_content": [], "media_thumbnail": [], "id": 1, "text": "DUBAI, October 11. /TASS/. Israel would like nothing more than to see a full-on war between Iran and the United States but Tehran won't give it the satisfaction, General Hossein Daghighi, a top advisor to the chief commander of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), said. \"A war between Iran and the United States is one of the long-cherished goals of the Zionist regime (Israel - TASS), but today, the Zionist regime is in a very weak and fragile state. A war on Iran is inadmissible and we reassure the Iranian people that the Islamic republic’s armed forces are strong and are keeping an ear to the ground,\" the Tasmin agency quoted him as saying. \"Security is a redline for Iran. The Zionist regime will inevitably be defeated and Iran will win,\" he stressed, adding that the October 1 missile attack on Israel has disabled Israel’s Iron Dome air defense system. He warned that new attacks on Israel will be \"more crushing.\" Commenting on reports in the Western media about the \"disappearance\" of Iranian Quds Force commander Esmail Qaani after the Israeli attack on Beirut two weeks ago, Daghighi said, \"Iran is a strong and powerful country and we must fend off enemy rumors and psychological warfare, and the mass media play an important and effective role in this.\" \"His absence means that he is focused on implementing the duties of the Islamic republic’s armed forces,\" the general said. Reuters reported on October 6, citing sources, that the Quds Force commander had been out of reach after Israel’ strikes on Beirut. According to the sources, Qaani reportedly set off for Lebanon following the death of Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah on September 27. On October 1, Iran launched a massive missile attack against the Jewish state in response to the killing of senior officials from the Palestinian movement Hamas, the Lebanon-based Shia movement Hezbollah and the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC). Tehran said that 90% of the missiles hit their designated targets. Israel, in turn, said that Iran had fired some 180 missiles into the country, most of which were intercepted. The Israeli General Staff vowed to choose the right moment to surprise Iran with a counterattack, while Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei warned that Israel would see even larger-scale strikes.", "ner": [{"sentence": "Israel would like nothing more than to see a full-on war between Iran and the United States but Tehran won't give it the satisfaction, General Hossein Daghighi, a top advisor to the chief commander of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.89", "spans": [{"text": "Israel", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.71"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 65, "end": 69, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "the United States", "start": 74, "end": 91, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.73"}, {"text": "Tehran", "start": 96, "end": 102, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "Hossein Daghighi", "start": 143, "end": 159, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.83"}, {"text": "the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps", "start": 201, "end": 238, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.76"}, {"text": "IRGC", "start": 240, "end": 244, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.83"}]}, {"sentence": "\"A war between Iran and the United States is one of the long-cherished goals of the Zionist regime (Israel - TASS), but today, the Zionist regime is in a very weak and fragile state.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "Iran", "start": 15, "end": 19, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.73"}, {"text": "the United States", "start": 24, "end": 41, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.73"}, {"text": "Zionist", "start": 84, "end": 91, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "today", "start": 120, "end": 125, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.85"}, {"text": "Zionist", "start": 131, "end": 138, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.96"}]}, {"sentence": "A war on Iran is inadmissible and we reassure the Iranian people that the Islamic republic’s armed forces are strong and are keeping an ear to the ground,\" the Tasmin agency quoted him as saying.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.93", "spans": [{"text": "Iran", "start": 9, "end": 13, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.52"}, {"text": "Iranian", "start": 50, "end": 57, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.56"}, {"text": "Islamic", "start": 74, "end": 81, "value": "NORP", "score": "0.97", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.84"}, {"text": "Tasmin", "start": 160, "end": 166, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.86"}]}, {"sentence": "\"Security is a redline for Iran.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.97", "spans": [{"text": "Iran", "start": 27, "end": 31, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.83"}]}, {"sentence": "The Zionist regime will inevitably be defeated and Iran will win,\" he stressed, adding that the October 1 missile attack on Israel has disabled Israel’s Iron Dome air defense system.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.98", "spans": [{"text": "Zionist", "start": 4, "end": 11, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.84"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 51, "end": 55, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.41"}, {"text": "October 1", "start": 96, "end": 105, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.54"}, {"text": "Israel", "start": 124, "end": 130, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.66"}, {"text": "Israel", "start": 144, "end": 150, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.63"}, {"text": "Iron Dome", "start": 153, "end": 162, "value": "PRODUCT", "score": "0.88", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.57"}]}, {"sentence": "He warned that new attacks on Israel will be \"more crushing.\"", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Israel", "start": 30, "end": 36, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.62"}]}, {"sentence": "Commenting on reports in the Western media about the \"disappearance\" of Iranian Quds Force commander Esmail Qaani after the Israeli attack on Beirut two weeks ago, Daghighi said, \"Iran is a strong and powerful country and we must fend off enemy rumors and psychological warfare, and the mass media play an important and effective role in this.\"", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.94", "spans": [{"text": "Western", "start": 29, "end": 36, "value": "NORP", "score": "0.99", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.70"}, {"text": "Iranian", "start": 72, "end": 79, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.69"}, {"text": "Quds Force", "start": 80, "end": 90, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.71"}, {"text": "Esmail Qaani", "start": 101, "end": 113, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "Israeli", "start": 124, "end": 131, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.85"}, {"text": "Beirut", "start": 142, "end": 148, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.61"}, {"text": "two weeks ago", "start": 149, "end": 162, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.55"}, {"text": "Daghighi", "start": 164, "end": 172, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 180, "end": 184, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.68"}]}, {"sentence": "\"His absence means that he is focused on implementing the duties of the Islamic republic’s armed forces,\" the general said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "Islamic", "start": 72, "end": 79, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}]}, {"sentence": "Reuters reported on October 6, citing sources, that the Quds Force commander had been out of reach after Israel’ strikes on Beirut.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Reuters", "start": 0, "end": 7, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}, {"text": "October 6", "start": 20, "end": 29, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}, {"text": "Quds Force", "start": 56, "end": 66, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}, {"text": "Israel’", "start": 105, "end": 112, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.87"}, {"text": "Beirut", "start": 124, "end": 130, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}]}, {"sentence": "According to the sources, Qaani reportedly set off for Lebanon following the death of Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah on September 27.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.94", "spans": [{"text": "Qaani", "start": 26, "end": 31, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.91"}, {"text": "Lebanon", "start": 55, "end": 62, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "Hezbollah", "start": 86, "end": 95, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.51"}, {"text": "Hassan Nasrallah", "start": 103, "end": 119, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.84"}, {"text": "September 27", "start": 123, "end": 135, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.94"}]}, {"sentence": "On October 1, Iran launched a massive missile attack against the Jewish state in response to the killing of senior officials from the Palestinian movement Hamas, the Lebanon-based Shia movement Hezbollah and the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC).", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "October 1", "start": 3, "end": 12, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.83"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 14, "end": 18, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "Jewish", "start": 65, "end": 71, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.72"}, {"text": "Palestinian", "start": 134, "end": 145, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.88"}, {"text": "Hamas", "start": 155, "end": 160, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.94"}, {"text": "Lebanon-based", "start": 166, "end": 179, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.54"}, {"text": "Shia", "start": 180, "end": 184, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "Hezbollah", "start": 194, "end": 203, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.91"}, {"text": "the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps", "start": 208, "end": 245, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "IRGC", "start": 247, "end": 251, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.84"}]}, {"sentence": "Tehran said that 90% of the missiles hit their designated targets.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Tehran", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "90%", "start": 17, "end": 20, "value": "PERCENT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.82"}]}, {"sentence": "The Israeli General Staff vowed to choose the right moment to surprise Iran with a counterattack, while Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei warned that Israel would see even larger-scale strikes.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.80", "spans": [{"text": "The Israeli General Staff", "start": 0, "end": 25, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.73"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 71, "end": 75, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}, {"text": "Iranian", "start": 104, "end": 111, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.85"}, {"text": "Ayatollah Ali Khamenei", "start": 127, "end": 149, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.84"}, {"text": "Israel", "start": 162, "end": 168, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.73"}]}]}
{"lang": "en", "source": "tass", "title": "Ukraine’s losses, reconnaissance unit’s elimination: unfolding situation in Kursk Region", "link": "https://tass.com/politics/1855173", "tags": ["Russian Politics & Diplomacy", "Military operation in Ukraine"], "flavor": "art", "published": "Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:36:48 +0300", "published_parsed": [2024, 10, 11, 13, 36, 48, 4, 285, 0], "summary": "The Russian military repelled five enemy attacks towards the settlements of Lyubimovka, Malaya Loknya, Novaya Sorochina and Kremyanoye", "media_content": [], "media_thumbnail": [], "id": 2, "text": "MOSCOW, October 11. /TASS/. The Ukrainian armed forces lost more than 300 servicemen in the Kursk area over the past day, and 21,900 since the start of the hostilities in the region, the Russian Defense Ministry reported. The Russian marines have destroyed a Ukrainian reconnaissance unit in the Kursk border region, the military told TASS. TASS has summed up information about the situation. - The Russian military repelled five enemy attacks towards the settlements of Lyubimovka, Malaya Loknya, Novaya Sorochina and Kremyanoye. - Russia's Battlegroup North units continued offensive operations and destroyed Ukrainian formations in the areas of Daryino, Lyubimovka, Tolsty Lug, Novy Put and Plekhovo. - The Russian Armed Forces struck clusters of manpower and equipment in the areas of Bondarevka, Goncharovka, Daryino, Zazulevka, Kurilovka, Leonidovo, Lyubimovka, Malaya Loknya, Martynovka, Makhnovka, Nikolayevo-Daryino, Novy Put, Nizhny Klin, Novoivanovka, Orlovka, Plekhovo, Sverdlikovo, Tolsty Lug and Cherkasskoye Porechnoye. - Tactical air and missile forces struck Ukrainian reserves in the Sumy region. - The operation to wipe out the enemy forces continues. - Over the day, the enemy lost more than 300 servicemen, 13 units of armored vehicles, among them five tanks, three infantry fighting vehicles, five armored combat vehicles, as well as 4 pieces of artillery, a multiple rocket launcher, a mortar, an electronic warfare station and four motor vehicles. One Ukrainian serviceman surrendered as a prisoner of war (POW). - Since the beginning of hostilities in the Kursk Region, Kiev has lost over 21,900 servicemen, 144 tanks, 69 infantry fighting vehicles, 98 armored personnel carriers, 897 armored combat vehicles, 594 motor vehicles, 181 artillery guns, 34 multiple rocket launchers, including eight HIMARS and six US-made MLRS, nine launchers of anti-aircraft missile systems, five transport and loading vehicles, 47 electronic warfare stations, nine counter-battery radars, three air defense radars, 22 pieces of engineering and other equipment, including 13 engineering demolition vehicles, a UR-77 demining unit, and three armored repair vehicles. - The Russian marines destroyed a Ukrainian reconnaissance unit in the Kursk border region, taking three Ukrainian military personnel as POWs, the military told TASS.", "ner": [{"sentence": "MOSCOW, October 11.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.89", "spans": [{"text": "MOSCOW", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.99"}, {"text": "October 11", "start": 8, "end": 18, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}]}, {"sentence": "The Ukrainian armed forces lost more than 300 servicemen in the Kursk area over the past day, and 21,900 since the start of the hostilities in the region, the Russian Defense Ministry reported.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.97", "spans": [{"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 4, "end": 13, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.49"}, {"text": "more than 300", "start": 32, "end": 45, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.57"}, {"text": "Kursk", "start": 64, "end": 69, "value": "GPE", "score": "0.88", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}, {"text": "the past day", "start": 80, "end": 92, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.85"}, {"text": "21,900", "start": 98, "end": 104, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}, {"text": "the Russian Defense Ministry", "start": 155, "end": 183, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}]}, {"sentence": "The Russian marines have destroyed a Ukrainian reconnaissance unit in the Kursk border region, the military told TASS.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Russian", "start": 4, "end": 11, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.88"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 37, "end": 46, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}, {"text": "Kursk", "start": 74, "end": 79, "value": "GPE", "score": "0.99", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "TASS", "start": 113, "end": 117, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}]}, {"sentence": "TASS has summed up information about the situation.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.98", "spans": [{"text": "TASS", "start": 0, "end": 4, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.99"}]}, {"sentence": "- The Russian military repelled five enemy attacks towards the settlements of Lyubimovka, Malaya Loknya, Novaya Sorochina and Kremyanoye.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.98", "spans": [{"text": "Russian", "start": 6, "end": 13, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.48"}, {"text": "five", "start": 32, "end": 36, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "Lyubimovka", "start": 78, "end": 88, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}, {"text": "Malaya Loknya", "start": 90, "end": 103, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.90"}, {"text": "Novaya Sorochina", "start": 105, "end": 121, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "Kremyanoye", "start": 126, "end": 136, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.91"}]}, {"sentence": "- Russia's Battlegroup North units continued offensive operations and destroyed Ukrainian formations in the areas of Daryino, Lyubimovka, Tolsty Lug, Novy Put and Plekhovo.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "Russia", "start": 2, "end": 8, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.65"}, {"text": "Battlegroup North", "start": 11, "end": 28, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.71"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 80, "end": 89, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.74"}, {"text": "Daryino", "start": 117, "end": 124, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "Lyubimovka", "start": 126, "end": 136, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.87"}, {"text": "Tolsty Lug", "start": 138, "end": 148, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.81"}, {"text": "Novy Put", "start": 150, "end": 158, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.88"}, {"text": "Plekhovo", "start": 163, "end": 171, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.94"}]}, {"sentence": "- The Russian Armed Forces struck clusters of manpower and equipment in the areas of Bondarevka, Goncharovka, Daryino, Zazulevka, Kurilovka, Leonidovo, Lyubimovka, Malaya Loknya, Martynovka, Makhnovka, Nikolayevo-Daryino, Novy Put, Nizhny Klin, Novoivanovka, Orlovka, Plekhovo, Sverdlikovo, Tolsty Lug and Cherkasskoye Porechnoye.", "tag": "positive", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "The Russian Armed Forces", "start": 2, "end": 26, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.66"}, {"text": "Bondarevka", "start": 85, "end": 95, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.78"}, {"text": "Goncharovka", "start": 97, "end": 108, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.78"}, {"text": "Daryino", "start": 110, "end": 117, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}, {"text": "Zazulevka", "start": 119, "end": 128, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.77"}, {"text": "Kurilovka", "start": 130, "end": 139, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}, {"text": "Leonidovo", "start": 141, "end": 150, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.81"}, {"text": "Lyubimovka", "start": 152, "end": 162, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.79"}, {"text": "Malaya Loknya", "start": 164, "end": 177, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.81"}, {"text": "Martynovka", "start": 179, "end": 189, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.77"}, {"text": "Makhnovka", "start": 191, "end": 200, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.78"}, {"text": "Nikolayevo-Daryino", "start": 202, "end": 220, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.83"}, {"text": "Novy Put", "start": 222, "end": 230, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.79"}, {"text": "Nizhny Klin", "start": 232, "end": 243, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.78"}, {"text": "Novoivanovka", "start": 245, "end": 257, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.73"}, {"text": "Orlovka", "start": 259, "end": 266, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.76"}, {"text": "Plekhovo", "start": 268, "end": 276, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.72"}, {"text": "Sverdlikovo", "start": 278, "end": 289, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.76"}, {"text": "Tolsty Lug", "start": 291, "end": 301, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.72"}, {"text": "Cherkasskoye Porechnoye", "start": 306, "end": 329, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.71"}]}, {"sentence": "- Tactical air and missile forces struck Ukrainian reserves in the Sumy region.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.91", "spans": [{"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 41, "end": 50, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.91"}, {"text": "Sumy", "start": 67, "end": 71, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}]}, {"sentence": "- The operation to wipe out the enemy forces continues.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.90", "spans": []}, {"sentence": "- Over the day, the enemy lost more than 300 servicemen, 13 units of armored vehicles, among them five tanks, three infantry fighting vehicles, five armored combat vehicles, as well as 4 pieces of artillery, a multiple rocket launcher, a mortar, an electronic warfare station and four motor vehicles.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "the day", "start": 7, "end": 14, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.70"}, {"text": "more than 300", "start": 31, "end": 44, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.55"}, {"text": "13", "start": 57, "end": 59, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.48"}, {"text": "five", "start": 98, "end": 102, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "three", "start": 110, "end": 115, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.56"}, {"text": "five", "start": 144, "end": 148, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "4", "start": 185, "end": 186, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.52"}, {"text": "four", "start": 280, "end": 284, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.59"}]}, {"sentence": "One Ukrainian serviceman surrendered as a prisoner of war (POW).", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.91", "spans": [{"text": "One", "start": 0, "end": 3, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.70"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 4, "end": 13, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.58"}]}, {"sentence": "- Since the beginning of hostilities in the Kursk Region, Kiev has lost over 21,900 servicemen, 144 tanks, 69 infantry fighting vehicles, 98 armored personnel carriers, 897 armored combat vehicles, 594 motor vehicles, 181 artillery guns, 34 multiple rocket launchers, including eight HIMARS and six US-made MLRS, nine launchers of anti-aircraft missile systems, five transport and loading vehicles, 47 electronic warfare stations, nine counter-battery radars, three air defense radars, 22 pieces of engineering and other equipment, including 13 engineering demolition vehicles, a UR-77 demining unit, and three armored repair vehicles.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.76", "spans": [{"text": "the Kursk Region", "start": 40, "end": 56, "value": "LOC", "score": "0.95", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.86"}, {"text": "Kiev", "start": 58, "end": 62, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "21,900", "start": 77, "end": 83, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "0.58", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.50"}, {"text": "144", "start": 96, "end": 99, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.51"}, {"text": "69", "start": 107, "end": 109, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "98", "start": 138, "end": 140, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.51"}, {"text": "897", "start": 169, "end": 172, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "594", "start": 198, "end": 201, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "181", "start": 218, "end": 221, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "34", "start": 238, "end": 240, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "eight", "start": 278, "end": 283, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "0.99", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "HIMARS", "start": 284, "end": 290, "value": "PRODUCT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.47"}, {"text": "six", "start": 295, "end": 298, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "US-made", "start": 299, "end": 306, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "MLRS", "start": 307, "end": 311, "value": "PRODUCT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "nine", "start": 313, "end": 317, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "five", "start": 362, "end": 366, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "47", "start": 399, "end": 401, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "nine", "start": 431, "end": 435, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "three", "start": 460, "end": 465, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.54"}, {"text": "22", "start": 486, "end": 488, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.54"}, {"text": "13", "start": 542, "end": 544, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "UR-77", "start": 580, "end": 585, "value": "PRODUCT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.60"}, {"text": "three", "start": 605, "end": 610, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.54"}]}, {"sentence": "- The Russian marines destroyed a Ukrainian reconnaissance unit in the Kursk border region, taking three Ukrainian military personnel as POWs, the military told TASS.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Russian", "start": 6, "end": 13, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.94"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 34, "end": 43, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}, {"text": "Kursk", "start": 71, "end": 76, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}, {"text": "three", "start": 99, "end": 104, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.63"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 105, "end": 114, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}, {"text": "TASS", "start": 161, "end": 165, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}]}]}
{"lang": "en", "source": "tass", "title": "Gulf states seek to avoid war in region by allying with Iran — media", "link": "https://tass.com/world/1855171", "tags": ["World", "Middle East conflict"], "flavor": "art", "published": "Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:35:00 +0300", "published_parsed": [2024, 10, 11, 13, 35, 0, 4, 285, 0], "summary": "Anna Jacobs noted that the Gulf countries are trying not to be drawn into the conflict in the Middle East and are making sure that \"Israel doesn't use any of their airspace for any attacks\"", "media_content": [], "media_thumbnail": [], "id": 3, "text": "PARIS, October 11. /TASS/. Gulf countries have strengthened their ties with Iran and are working to reassure Tehran that they will not support Israel, aiming to avoid involvement in the Middle East conflict, regional experts told the AFP news agency in a commentary. \"Gulf states are trying to leverage improved relations with Iran to avoid being caught in the middle of an Israel-Iran escalation,\" Anna Jacobs, an expert at the International Crisis Group think tank, told the agency. The analyst added that the Gulf countries are trying not to be drawn into the conflict in the Middle East and are making sure that \"Israel doesn't use any of their airspace for any attacks.\" According to Ali Shihabi, an expert close to the Saudi government, the kingdom in particular intends to confirm that it \"will not allow any party to use its airspace to attack the other.\" Reuters reported on October 9 that Iran warned Gulf states of their responsibility to provide military assistance or airspace to Israel in an alleged Israeli retaliatory attack in response to a recent Iranian missile strike. According to the agency's source, Iran issued this warning during Islamic Republic President Masoud Pezeshkian's visit to Qatar on October 3. On the evening of October 1, Iran launched a massive missile attack on Israel as a response for the killings of the key leaders of Hamas, Hezbollah and the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps. Tehran claimed that 90% of the missiles hit their intended targets, while Israel said that Iran only launched 180 missiles and most of them were intercepted.", "ner": [{"sentence": "PARIS, October 11.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.65", "spans": [{"text": "PARIS", "start": 0, "end": 5, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.99"}, {"text": "October 11", "start": 7, "end": 17, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}]}, {"sentence": "Gulf countries have strengthened their ties with Iran and are working to reassure Tehran that they will not support Israel, aiming to avoid involvement in the Middle East conflict, regional experts told the AFP news agency in a commentary.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.92", "spans": [{"text": "Gulf", "start": 0, "end": 4, "value": "LOC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.69"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 49, "end": 53, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.50"}, {"text": "Tehran", "start": 82, "end": 88, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.60"}, {"text": "Israel", "start": 116, "end": 122, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.49"}, {"text": "Middle East", "start": 159, "end": 170, "value": "LOC", "score": "0.89", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.87"}, {"text": "AFP", "start": 207, "end": 210, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}]}, {"sentence": "\"Gulf states are trying to leverage improved relations with Iran to avoid being caught in the middle of an Israel-Iran escalation,\" Anna Jacobs, an expert at the International Crisis Group think tank, told the agency.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.98", "spans": [{"text": "Gulf", "start": 1, "end": 5, "value": "LOC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.52"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 60, "end": 64, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.59"}, {"text": "Israel-Iran", "start": 107, "end": 118, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.62"}, {"text": "Anna Jacobs", "start": 132, "end": 143, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.84"}, {"text": "International Crisis Group", "start": 162, "end": 188, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.90"}]}, {"sentence": "The analyst added that the Gulf countries are trying not to be drawn into the conflict in the Middle East and are making sure that \"Israel doesn't use any of their airspace for any attacks.\"", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "Gulf", "start": 27, "end": 31, "value": "LOC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}, {"text": "the Middle East", "start": 90, "end": 105, "value": "LOC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.90"}, {"text": "Israel", "start": 132, "end": 138, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.76"}]}, {"sentence": "According to Ali Shihabi, an expert close to the Saudi government, the kingdom in particular intends to confirm that it \"will not allow any party to use its airspace to attack the other.\"", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Ali Shihabi", "start": 13, "end": 24, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "Saudi", "start": 49, "end": 54, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}]}, {"sentence": "Reuters reported on October 9 that Iran warned Gulf states of their responsibility to provide military assistance or airspace to Israel in an alleged Israeli retaliatory attack in response to a recent Iranian missile strike.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "Reuters", "start": 0, "end": 7, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "October 9", "start": 20, "end": 29, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 35, "end": 39, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "Gulf", "start": 47, "end": 51, "value": "LOC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.82"}, {"text": "Israel", "start": 129, "end": 135, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.62"}, {"text": "Israeli", "start": 150, "end": 157, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.78"}, {"text": "Iranian", "start": 201, "end": 208, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.52"}]}, {"sentence": "According to the agency's source, Iran issued this warning during Islamic Republic President Masoud Pezeshkian's visit to Qatar on October 3.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Iran", "start": 34, "end": 38, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}, {"text": "Islamic Republic", "start": 66, "end": 82, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "Masoud Pezeshkian", "start": 93, "end": 110, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "Qatar", "start": 122, "end": 127, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}, {"text": "October 3", "start": 131, "end": 140, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}]}, {"sentence": "On the evening of October 1, Iran launched a massive missile attack on Israel as a response for the killings of the key leaders of Hamas, Hezbollah and the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "the evening of October 1", "start": 3, "end": 27, "value": "TIME", "score": "0.90", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 29, "end": 33, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.94"}, {"text": "Israel", "start": 71, "end": 77, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "Hamas", "start": 131, "end": 136, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.94"}, {"text": "Hezbollah", "start": 138, "end": 147, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps", "start": 152, "end": 189, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.86"}]}, {"sentence": "Tehran claimed that 90% of the missiles hit their intended targets, while Israel said that Iran only launched 180 missiles and most of them were intercepted.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Tehran", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.81"}, {"text": "90%", "start": 20, "end": 23, "value": "PERCENT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.68"}, {"text": "Israel", "start": 74, "end": 80, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "Iran", "start": 91, "end": 95, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.87"}, {"text": "180", "start": 110, "end": 113, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.58"}]}]}
{"lang": "en", "source": "tass", "title": "Strategic partnership between Moscow, Ashgabat thrives — Putin", "link": "https://tass.com/politics/1855165", "tags": ["FOREIGN POLICY", "Russian Politics & Diplomacy"], "flavor": "art", "published": "Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:32:14 +0300", "published_parsed": [2024, 10, 11, 13, 32, 14, 4, 285, 0], "summary": "The Russian president praised the development of trade and economic ties between Russia and Turkmenistan", "media_content": [], "media_thumbnail": [], "id": 4, "text": "ASHGABAT, October 11. /TASS/. Russia and Turkmenistan have a budding strategic partnership on their hands, Russian President Vladimir Putin said. Putin held a meeting with Chairman of Turkmenistan's Khalk Maslahaty (People's Council) and former President of Turkmenistan Gurbanguly Berdimuhamedov in Ashgabat. \"The strategic partnership is developing successfully between Russia and Turkmenistan. Largely thanks to your efforts, as you have set a model of such relations,\" Putin said at the meeting. The Russian president praised the development of trade and economic ties between Russia and Turkmenistan. According to Putin, Moscow and Ashgabat keep looking for new projects aimed at developing their relations, and have an intergovernmental commission for just this purpose. Putin also pointed at close interregional ties. \"Interregional relations are developing well. As many as 60 federal subjects of Russia have strong ties with their friends and partners in Turkmenistan,\" the Russian president said, noting that Tatarstan, the Astrakhan Region and St. Petersburg work closely with Turkmenistan. Putin also assured the former president of Turkmenistan of good relations with Serdar Berdimuhamedov, the country's current leader, who is expected at the BRICS Summit in Kazan, as well as at the informal summit of CIS leaders on New Year's Eve.", "ner": [{"sentence": "ASHGABAT, October 11.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.88", "spans": [{"text": "ASHGABAT", "start": 0, "end": 8, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.99"}, {"text": "October 11", "start": 10, "end": 20, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}]}, {"sentence": "Russia and Turkmenistan have a budding strategic partnership on their hands, Russian President Vladimir Putin said.", "tag": "positive", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Russia", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.70"}, {"text": "Turkmenistan", "start": 11, "end": 23, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.74"}, {"text": "Russian", "start": 77, "end": 84, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.72"}, {"text": "Vladimir Putin", "start": 95, "end": 109, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}]}, {"sentence": "Putin held a meeting with Chairman of Turkmenistan's Khalk Maslahaty (People's Council) and former President of Turkmenistan Gurbanguly Berdimuhamedov in Ashgabat.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.74", "spans": [{"text": "Putin", "start": 0, "end": 5, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "Turkmenistan", "start": 38, "end": 50, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "Khalk Maslahaty", "start": 53, "end": 68, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "People's Council", "start": 70, "end": 86, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "Turkmenistan", "start": 112, "end": 124, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "Gurbanguly Berdimuhamedov", "start": 125, "end": 150, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "Ashgabat", "start": 154, "end": 162, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}]}, {"sentence": "\"The strategic partnership is developing successfully between Russia and Turkmenistan.", "tag": "positive", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Russia", "start": 62, "end": 68, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.60"}, {"text": "Turkmenistan", "start": 73, "end": 85, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.78"}]}, {"sentence": "Largely thanks to your efforts, as you have set a model of such relations,\" Putin said at the meeting.", "tag": "positive", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Putin", "start": 76, "end": 81, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.50"}]}, {"sentence": "The Russian president praised the development of trade and economic ties between Russia and Turkmenistan.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.98", "spans": [{"text": "Russian", "start": 4, "end": 11, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.67"}, {"text": "Russia", "start": 81, "end": 87, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.63"}, {"text": "Turkmenistan", "start": 92, "end": 104, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}]}, {"sentence": "According to Putin, Moscow and Ashgabat keep looking for new projects aimed at developing their relations, and have an intergovernmental commission for just this purpose.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.72", "spans": [{"text": "Putin", "start": 13, "end": 18, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.62"}, {"text": "Moscow", "start": 20, "end": 26, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.70"}, {"text": "Ashgabat", "start": 31, "end": 39, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.60"}]}, {"sentence": "Putin also pointed at close interregional ties.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.94", "spans": [{"text": "Putin", "start": 0, "end": 5, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.68"}]}, {"sentence": "\"Interregional relations are developing well.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.99", "spans": []}, {"sentence": "As many as 60 federal subjects of Russia have strong ties with their friends and partners in Turkmenistan,\" the Russian president said, noting that Tatarstan, the Astrakhan Region and St. Petersburg work closely with Turkmenistan.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "As many as 60", "start": 0, "end": 13, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "0.91", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.50"}, {"text": "Russia", "start": 34, "end": 40, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.70"}, {"text": "Turkmenistan", "start": 93, "end": 105, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.88"}, {"text": "Russian", "start": 112, "end": 119, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.70"}, {"text": "Tatarstan", "start": 148, "end": 157, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.76"}, {"text": "the Astrakhan Region", "start": 159, "end": 179, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.86"}, {"text": "St. Petersburg", "start": 184, "end": 198, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.87"}, {"text": "Turkmenistan", "start": 217, "end": 229, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.88"}]}, {"sentence": "Putin also assured the former president of Turkmenistan of good relations with Serdar Berdimuhamedov, the country's current leader, who is expected at the BRICS Summit in Kazan, as well as at the informal summit of CIS leaders on New Year's Eve.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.81", "spans": [{"text": "Putin", "start": 0, "end": 5, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.69"}, {"text": "Turkmenistan", "start": 43, "end": 55, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.77"}, {"text": "Serdar Berdimuhamedov", "start": 79, "end": 100, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.60"}, {"text": "the BRICS Summit", "start": 151, "end": 167, "value": "EVENT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.86"}, {"text": "Kazan", "start": 171, "end": 176, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.91"}, {"text": "CIS", "start": 215, "end": 218, "value": "ORG", "score": "0.99", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.85"}, {"text": "New Year's Eve", "start": 230, "end": 244, "value": "DATE", "score": "0.96", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.85"}]}]}
{"lang": "en", "source": "tass", "title": "Bank of Russia sells yuan worth $54.5 mln with settlements on October 10", "link": "https://tass.com/economy/1855169", "tags": ["Business & Economy"], "flavor": "art", "published": "Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:31:24 +0300", "published_parsed": [2024, 10, 11, 13, 31, 24, 4, 285, 0], "summary": "Sales of currency on the domestic market with settlements on October 9 also amounted to 5.3 bln rubles", "media_content": [], "media_thumbnail": [], "id": 5, "text": "MOSCOW, October 11. /TASS/. The Bank of Russia sold yuan on the domestic market with settlements on October 10, 2024, in the amount of for 5.3 billion rubles ($54.5 mln), according to data on the regulator's website. Sales of currency on the domestic market with settlements on October 9 also amounted to 5.3 bln rubles. The Bank of Russia carries out purchase and sale operations on the domestic market in the currency section of the Moscow Exchange in the yuan-ruble instrument. They are held from September 6, 2024 to October 4, 2024. The daily volume of transactions in 2024 will be determined based on the volumes of purchases or sales of foreign currency announced by the Russian Ministry of Finance on the third working day of each month within the framework of regular transactions in accordance with the budget rule, adjusted for the balanced value of a number of transactions.", "ner": [{"sentence": "MOSCOW, October 11.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.89", "spans": [{"text": "MOSCOW", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.99"}, {"text": "October 11", "start": 8, "end": 18, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}]}, {"sentence": "The Bank of Russia sold yuan on the domestic market with settlements on October 10, 2024, in the amount of for 5.3 billion rubles ($54.5 mln), according to data on the regulator's website.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "The Bank of Russia", "start": 0, "end": 18, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}, {"text": "October 10, 2024", "start": 72, "end": 88, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}, {"text": "5.3 billion rubles", "start": 111, "end": 129, "value": "MONEY", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.80"}, {"text": "54.5 mln", "start": 132, "end": 140, "value": "MONEY", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.84"}]}, {"sentence": "Sales of currency on the domestic market with settlements on October 9 also amounted to 5.3 bln rubles.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "October 9", "start": 61, "end": 70, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}, {"text": "5.3 bln rubles", "start": 88, "end": 102, "value": "MONEY", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.79"}]}, {"sentence": "The Bank of Russia carries out purchase and sale operations on the domestic market in the currency section of the Moscow Exchange in the yuan-ruble instrument.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "The Bank of Russia", "start": 0, "end": 18, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.51"}, {"text": "the Moscow Exchange", "start": 110, "end": 129, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}]}, {"sentence": "They are held from September 6, 2024 to October 4, 2024.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.83", "spans": [{"text": "September 6, 2024 to October 4, 2024", "start": 19, "end": 55, "value": "DATE", "score": "0.98", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}]}, {"sentence": "The daily volume of transactions in 2024 will be determined based on the volumes of purchases or sales of foreign currency announced by the Russian Ministry of Finance on the third working day of each month within the framework of regular transactions in accordance with the budget rule, adjusted for the balanced value of a number of transactions.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.88", "spans": [{"text": "2024", "start": 36, "end": 40, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.83"}, {"text": "the Russian Ministry of Finance", "start": 136, "end": 167, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.88"}, {"text": "the third working day", "start": 171, "end": 192, "value": "DATE", "score": "0.93", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.85"}]}]}
{"lang": "en", "source": "tass", "title": "WHO not recommending trade restrictions due to Mpox, Marburg fever outbreaks", "link": "https://tass.com/world/1855161", "tags": ["World", "Business & Economy", "Trade & Cooperation"], "flavor": "art", "published": "Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:25:12 +0300", "published_parsed": [2024, 10, 11, 13, 25, 12, 4, 285, 0], "summary": "\"Priority should be given to public health advice and concerted, collaborative public health efforts by all partners to contain the outbreaks and protect people everywhere,\" WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus added", "media_content": [], "media_thumbnail": [], "id": 6, "text": "GENEVA, October 11. /TASS/. The World Health Organization (WHO) does not recommend introducing restrictions of trade and travel to countries where Mpox [new name of monkeypox] and Marburg fever cases were recorded, WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus wrote on the X social network. \"Based on the current Mpox and Marburg outbreaks risk assessments, WHO advises that no travel and trade restrictions are needed,\" he said. \"Priority should be given to public health advice and concerted, collaborative public health efforts by all partners to contain the outbreaks and protect people everywhere,\" Ghebreyesus added. According to WHO data, more than 35,000 cases of suspected Mpox and almost a thousand lethal outcomes that may occur due to this disease were found in Africa from January 1 to September 24. On September 27, Rwanda’s Ministry of Health confirms the start of the Marburg fever outbreak in the country.", "ner": [{"sentence": "GENEVA, October 11.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.87", "spans": [{"text": "GENEVA", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.99"}, {"text": "October 11", "start": 8, "end": 18, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}]}, {"sentence": "The World Health Organization (WHO) does not recommend introducing restrictions of trade and travel to countries where Mpox [new name of monkeypox] and Marburg fever cases were recorded, WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus wrote on the X social network.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "The World Health Organization", "start": 0, "end": 29, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "WHO", "start": 31, "end": 34, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "WHO", "start": 187, "end": 190, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.92"}, {"text": "Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus", "start": 208, "end": 234, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}]}, {"sentence": "\"Based on the current Mpox and Marburg outbreaks risk assessments, WHO advises that no travel and trade restrictions are needed,\" he said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "WHO", "start": 67, "end": 70, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.81"}]}, {"sentence": "\"Priority should be given to public health advice and concerted, collaborative public health efforts by all partners to contain the outbreaks and protect people everywhere,\" Ghebreyesus added.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.91", "spans": [{"text": "Ghebreyesus", "start": 174, "end": 185, "value": "PERSON", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.64"}]}, {"sentence": "According to WHO data, more than 35,000 cases of suspected Mpox and almost a thousand lethal outcomes that may occur due to this disease were found in Africa from January 1 to September 24.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "WHO", "start": 13, "end": 16, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}, {"text": "more than 35,000", "start": 23, "end": 39, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.78"}, {"text": "almost a thousand", "start": 68, "end": 85, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.67"}, {"text": "Africa", "start": 151, "end": 157, "value": "LOC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}, {"text": "January 1 to September 24", "start": 163, "end": 188, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.94"}]}, {"sentence": "On September 27, Rwanda’s Ministry of Health confirms the start of the Marburg fever outbreak in the country.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "September 27", "start": 3, "end": 15, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "Rwanda", "start": 17, "end": 23, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "Ministry of Health", "start": 26, "end": 44, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "Marburg", "start": 71, "end": 78, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.87"}]}]}
{"lang": "en", "source": "tass", "title": "Russia delivers 38 strikes at Ukrainian energy sites, military airfields over week", "link": "https://tass.com/politics/1855159", "tags": ["Russian Politics & Diplomacy", "Military operation in Ukraine"], "flavor": "art", "published": "Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:23:48 +0300", "published_parsed": [2024, 10, 11, 13, 23, 48, 4, 285, 0], "summary": "Russia’s Battlegroup South liberated three communities in the Donetsk People’s Republic over the week, the ministry reported", "media_content": [], "media_thumbnail": [], "id": 7, "text": "MOSCOW, October 11. /TASS/. Russian forces delivered 38 strikes by precision weapons, including Kinzhal hypersonic missiles and unmanned aerial vehicles at Ukrainian oil and gas and energy sites and military airfields over the week in the special military operation in Ukraine, Russia’s Defense Ministry reported on Friday. \"On October 5-11, the Russian Armed Forces delivered 38 combined strikes by precision weapons, including Kinzhal air-launched hypersonic ballistic missiles and attack unmanned aerial vehicles. The strikes targeted oil and gas and energy sites providing for the operation of Ukrainian military-industrial enterprises, and also military airfield infrastructure. In addition, the strikes hit production workshops and storage facilities of naval drones and unmanned aerial vehicles, fuel depots, ammunition and materiel warehouses and temporary deployment sites of Ukrainian army units, nationalist formations and foreign mercenaries,\" the ministry said in a statement. The Ukrainian army lost almost 14,500 troops in battles with Russian forces in all the frontline areas over the week, according to the latest data on the special military operation in Ukraine released by Russia’s Defense Ministry. The latest data indicate that the Ukrainian army suffered more than 2,090 casualties from Russia’s Battlegroup North, roughly 2,920 casualties from the Battlegroup West, about 4,790 casualties from the Battlegroup South, around 3,370 casualties from the Battlegroup Center, 780 casualties from the Battlegroup East and 480 casualties from the Battlegroup Dnepr, with its total weekly losses amounting to 14,430 personnel. Russia’s Battlegroup North liberated the settlements of Novaya Sorochina and Pokrovsky in the Kursk Region and inflicted roughly 2,090 casualties on Ukrainian troops in its area of responsibility over the week, the ministry reported. \"During the week, Battlegroup North units continued an operation to destroy Ukrainian armed formations in the Kursk Region, in which they liberated the settlements of Novaya Sorochina and Pokrovsky,\" the ministry said. Over the week, Russian aircraft, unmanned aerial vehicles and artillery inflicted casualties on six mechanized brigades, a tank brigade, three air assault brigades of the Ukrainian army, a marine infantry brigade, four territorial defense brigades and a National Guard brigade, it specified. Russia’s Battlegroup North units also inflicted damage in the Volchansk and Liptsy directions in the Kharkov Region on manpower and military hardware of a motorized infantry brigade, a jaeger brigade, an air assault brigade of the Ukrainian army, two territorial defense brigades and a National Guard brigade, the ministry said. The Ukrainian army’s losses in the Battlegroup North area of responsibility amounted to more than 2,090 personnel, nine tanks, 32 armored combat vehicles, 26 motor vehicles, a Czech-made Vampire multiple rocket launcher and 25 field artillery guns, it said. In addition, Russian forces destroyed five electronic warfare and counterbattery radar stations and two field ammunition depots of the Ukrainian army over the week, the ministry said. Russia’s Battlegroup West repelled 23 Ukrainian army counterattacks and inflicted more than 2,900 casualties on enemy troops in its area of responsibility over the week, the ministry reported. \"Over the week, Battlegroup West units continued advancing deep into the enemy’s defenses and gained more advantageous positions. They inflicted casualties on formations of two tank and six mechanized brigades, an assault brigade of the Ukrainian army, two territorial defense brigades and two National Guard brigades. They repelled 23 counterattacks by assault groups of the Ukrainian army,\" the ministry said. The Ukrainian army’s losses in that frontline area over the week amounted to 2,920 personnel, two tanks, 16 other armored combat vehicles, among them eight US-made M113 armored personnel carriers, 46 motor vehicles and 35 field artillery guns, including 11 NATO-supplied 155mm self-propelled artillery systems and howitzers, it specified. In addition, Russian forces destroyed 13 electronic warfare and counterbattery radar stations and 22 field ammunition depots of the Ukrainian army over the week, the ministry said. Russia’s Battlegroup South liberated three communities in the Donetsk People’s Republic over the week, the ministry reported. \"Battlegroup South units liberated the settlements of Zhelannoye Vtoroye and Ostrovskoye in the Donetsk People’s Republic as a result of decisive operations,\" the ministry said. Russia’s Defense Ministry reported on October 8 that Battlegroup South units had liberated the settlement of Zoryanoye Pervoye in the Donetsk People’s Republic. Over the week, Battlegroup South units inflicted damage on manpower and military hardware of five mechanized brigades, a motorized infantry brigade, two infantry brigades, an assault brigade, a mountain assault brigade, an air assault brigade and two airmobile brigades of the Ukrainian army, a territorial defense brigade and two National Guard brigades. They repelled 22 counterattacks by Ukrainian assault groups, it specified. The Ukrainian army’s losses in that frontline area over the week amounted to 4,790 personnel, four armored combat vehicles, 53 motor vehicles and 45 field artillery guns, among them 37 Western-made weapons, it said. In addition, Russian forces destroyed five electronic warfare stations and 10 field ammunition depots of the Ukrainian army over the week, the ministry said. Russia’s Battlegroup Center liberated the settlement of Grodovka in the Donetsk People’s Republic, repulsed 58 Ukrainian counterattacks and inflicted roughly 3,370 casualties on enemy troops in its area of responsibility over the week, the ministry reported. \"Battlegroup Center units liberated the settlement of Grodovka in the Donetsk People’s Republic in active operations. They inflicted casualties on formations of a tank brigade, seven mechanized brigades, a motorized infantry brigade, two infantry brigades, a jaeger brigade, an airborne brigade of the Ukrainian army, two marine infantry brigades, three territorial defense brigades and three National Guard brigades. They repulsed 58 counterattacks by enemy assault groups,\" the ministry said. The Ukrainian army’s losses in that frontline area over the week amounted to 3,370 personnel, four tanks, among them German-made Leopard and French-made AMX-10 tanks and 11 other armored combat vehicles, including an M113 armored personnel carrier and a Bradley infantry fighting vehicle of US manufacture, it specified. In addition, Russian forces destroyed 27 motor vehicles and 26 field artillery guns of the Ukrainian army over the week, it said. Russia’s Battlegroup East liberated the settlement of Zolotaya Niva in the Donetsk People’s Republic over the week, the ministry reported. \"Battlegroup East units liberated the settlement of Zolotaya Niva in the Donetsk People’s Republic as a result of well-coordinated operations,\" the ministry said. Over the week, Battlegroup East units inflicted damage on manpower and military hardware of two mechanized brigades, a motorized infantry brigade of the Ukrainian army, four territorial defense brigades and a National Guard brigade, it specified. Russia’s Battlegroup East inflicted roughly 780 casualties on Ukrainian troops in its area of responsibility over the week, the ministry reported. Battlegroup East units also repelled 10 counterattacks by assault groups of the Ukrainian army over the week, it said. The Ukrainian army’s losses in that frontline area over the week amounted to 780 personnel, five armored combat vehicles, among them two US-made M113 armored personnel carriers and 51 motor vehicles, the ministry specified. In addition, Russian forces destroyed 16 field artillery guns of the Ukrainian army over the week, including 12 NATO-produced weapons, it said. Russia’s Battlegroup Dnepr inflicted roughly 480 casualties on Ukrainian troops and destroyed four enemy ammunition depots in its area of responsibility over the week, the ministry reported. \"Battlegroup Dnepr units inflicted casualties on formations of two mechanized brigades, an infantry brigade, a mountain assault brigade of the Ukrainian army, a marine infantry brigade and four territorial defense brigades,\" the ministry said. The Ukrainian army’s losses in that frontline area over the week amounted to 480 personnel, 27 motor vehicles and 14 field artillery guns, it specified. In addition, Russian forces destroyed seven electronic warfare and counterbattery radar stations and four field ammunition depots of the Ukrainian army over the week, the ministry said. More than 40 Ukrainian soldiers surrendered to Russian troops over the week, the ministry reported. \"During the week, 43 Ukrainian servicemen surrendered at the engagement line,\" the ministry said. Russian air defense forces destroyed 603 Ukrainian fixed-wing unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs), 33 rockets of the US-made HIMARS multiple launch rocket system and three American ATACMS missiles over the week, the ministry reported. \"Over the week, air defense capabilities shot down three US-made ATACMS operational/tactical missiles, three French-made Hammer guided aerial bombs, an S-200 surface-to-air missile converted for striking ground targets, 33 US-made HIMARS rockets and 603 fixed-wing unmanned aerial vehicles,\" the ministry said. Overall, the Russian Armed Forces have destroyed 646 Ukrainian warplanes, 283 helicopters, 33,419 unmanned aerial vehicles, 582 surface-to-air missile systems, 18,607 tanks and other armored combat vehicles, 1,470 multiple rocket launchers, 15,988 field artillery guns and mortars and 27,145 special military motor vehicles since the start of the special military operation, the ministry reported.", "ner": [{"sentence": "MOSCOW, October 11.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.89", "spans": [{"text": "MOSCOW", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.99"}, {"text": "October 11", "start": 8, "end": 18, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.98"}]}, {"sentence": "Russian forces delivered 38 strikes by precision weapons, including Kinzhal hypersonic missiles and unmanned aerial vehicles at Ukrainian oil and gas and energy sites and military airfields over the week in the special military operation in Ukraine, Russia’s Defense Ministry reported on Friday.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.63", "spans": [{"text": "Russian", "start": 0, "end": 7, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.70"}, {"text": "38", "start": 25, "end": 27, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.47"}, {"text": "Kinzhal", "start": 68, "end": 75, "value": "PRODUCT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.57"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 128, "end": 137, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.90"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 195, "end": 203, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.87"}, {"text": "Ukraine", "start": 241, "end": 248, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.91"}, {"text": "Russia", "start": 250, "end": 256, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.78"}, {"text": "Defense Ministry", "start": 259, "end": 275, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "Friday", "start": 288, "end": 294, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}]}, {"sentence": "\"On October 5-11, the Russian Armed Forces delivered 38 combined strikes by precision weapons, including Kinzhal air-launched hypersonic ballistic missiles and attack unmanned aerial vehicles.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.98", "spans": [{"text": "October 5-11", "start": 4, "end": 16, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "the Russian Armed Forces", "start": 18, "end": 42, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.41"}, {"text": "38", "start": 53, "end": 55, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "Kinzhal", "start": 105, "end": 112, "value": "PRODUCT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.45"}]}, {"sentence": "The strikes targeted oil and gas and energy sites providing for the operation of Ukrainian military-industrial enterprises, and also military airfield infrastructure.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 81, "end": 90, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.77"}]}, {"sentence": "In addition, the strikes hit production workshops and storage facilities of naval drones and unmanned aerial vehicles, fuel depots, ammunition and materiel warehouses and temporary deployment sites of Ukrainian army units, nationalist formations and foreign mercenaries,\" the ministry said in a statement.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.64", "spans": [{"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 201, "end": 210, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.68"}]}, {"sentence": "The Ukrainian army lost almost 14,500 troops in battles with Russian forces in all the frontline areas over the week, according to the latest data on the special military operation in Ukraine released by Russia’s Defense Ministry.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.91", "spans": [{"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 4, "end": 13, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}, {"text": "almost 14,500", "start": 24, "end": 37, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.58"}, {"text": "Russian", "start": 61, "end": 68, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.73"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 108, "end": 116, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "Ukraine", "start": 184, "end": 191, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.82"}, {"text": "Russia", "start": 204, "end": 210, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.81"}, {"text": "Defense Ministry", "start": 213, "end": 229, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}]}, {"sentence": "The latest data indicate that the Ukrainian army suffered more than 2,090 casualties from Russia’s Battlegroup North, roughly 2,920 casualties from the Battlegroup West, about 4,790 casualties from the Battlegroup South, around 3,370 casualties from the Battlegroup Center, 780 casualties from the Battlegroup East and 480 casualties from the Battlegroup Dnepr, with its total weekly losses amounting to 14,430 personnel.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 34, "end": 43, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.69"}, {"text": "more than 2,090", "start": 58, "end": 73, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.66"}, {"text": "Russia", "start": 90, "end": 96, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.60"}, {"text": "Battlegroup North", "start": 99, "end": 116, "value": "EVENT", "score": "0.74", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.73"}, {"text": "roughly 2,920", "start": 118, "end": 131, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.68"}, {"text": "the Battlegroup West", "start": 148, "end": 168, "value": "EVENT", "score": "0.96", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.73"}, {"text": "about 4,790", "start": 170, "end": 181, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.69"}, {"text": "the Battlegroup South", "start": 198, "end": 219, "value": "EVENT", "score": "0.98", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}, {"text": "around 3,370", "start": 221, "end": 233, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.69"}, {"text": "the Battlegroup Center", "start": 250, "end": 272, "value": "FAC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.74"}, {"text": "780", "start": 274, "end": 277, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.67"}, {"text": "the Battlegroup East", "start": 294, "end": 314, "value": "EVENT", "score": "0.98", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.71"}, {"text": "480", "start": 319, "end": 322, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.66"}, {"text": "the Battlegroup Dnepr", "start": 339, "end": 360, "value": "EVENT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.68"}, {"text": "weekly", "start": 377, "end": 383, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.67"}, {"text": "14,430", "start": 404, "end": 410, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.66"}]}, {"sentence": "Russia’s Battlegroup North liberated the settlements of Novaya Sorochina and Pokrovsky in the Kursk Region and inflicted roughly 2,090 casualties on Ukrainian troops in its area of responsibility over the week, the ministry reported.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.91", "spans": [{"text": "Russia", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.74"}, {"text": "Battlegroup North", "start": 9, "end": 26, "value": "ORG", "score": "0.97", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.62"}, {"text": "Novaya Sorochina", "start": 56, "end": 72, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.91"}, {"text": "Pokrovsky", "start": 77, "end": 86, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.86"}, {"text": "the Kursk Region", "start": 90, "end": 106, "value": "LOC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "roughly 2,090", "start": 121, "end": 134, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.71"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 149, "end": 158, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.83"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 201, "end": 209, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.94"}]}, {"sentence": "\"During the week, Battlegroup North units continued an operation to destroy Ukrainian armed formations in the Kursk Region, in which they liberated the settlements of Novaya Sorochina and Pokrovsky,\" the ministry said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.95", "spans": [{"text": "the week", "start": 8, "end": 16, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "Battlegroup North", "start": 18, "end": 35, "value": "ORG", "score": "0.99", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.54"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 76, "end": 85, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "the Kursk Region", "start": 106, "end": 122, "value": "LOC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.94"}, {"text": "Novaya Sorochina", "start": 167, "end": 183, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "Pokrovsky", "start": 188, "end": 197, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.82"}]}, {"sentence": "Over the week, Russian aircraft, unmanned aerial vehicles and artillery inflicted casualties on six mechanized brigades, a tank brigade, three air assault brigades of the Ukrainian army, a marine infantry brigade, four territorial defense brigades and a National Guard brigade, it specified.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "the week", "start": 5, "end": 13, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "Russian", "start": 15, "end": 22, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "six", "start": 96, "end": 99, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.63"}, {"text": "three", "start": 137, "end": 142, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.60"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 171, "end": 180, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.82"}, {"text": "four", "start": 214, "end": 218, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.66"}, {"text": "National Guard", "start": 254, "end": 268, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.74"}]}, {"sentence": "Russia’s Battlegroup North units also inflicted damage in the Volchansk and Liptsy directions in the Kharkov Region on manpower and military hardware of a motorized infantry brigade, a jaeger brigade, an air assault brigade of the Ukrainian army, two territorial defense brigades and a National Guard brigade, the ministry said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Russia", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.51"}, {"text": "Battlegroup North", "start": 9, "end": 26, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.71"}, {"text": "Volchansk", "start": 62, "end": 71, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.92"}, {"text": "Liptsy", "start": 76, "end": 82, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.78"}, {"text": "the Kharkov Region", "start": 97, "end": 115, "value": "GPE", "score": "0.90", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 231, "end": 240, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.81"}, {"text": "two", "start": 247, "end": 250, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.71"}, {"text": "National Guard", "start": 286, "end": 300, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.72"}]}, {"sentence": "The Ukrainian army’s losses in the Battlegroup North area of responsibility amounted to more than 2,090 personnel, nine tanks, 32 armored combat vehicles, 26 motor vehicles, a Czech-made Vampire multiple rocket launcher and 25 field artillery guns, it said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 4, "end": 13, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.55"}, {"text": "Battlegroup North", "start": 35, "end": 52, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.91"}, {"text": "more than 2,090", "start": 88, "end": 103, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "nine", "start": 115, "end": 119, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.51"}, {"text": "32", "start": 127, "end": 129, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.56"}, {"text": "26", "start": 155, "end": 157, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.60"}, {"text": "Czech-made", "start": 176, "end": 186, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "Vampire", "start": 187, "end": 194, "value": "PRODUCT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.66"}, {"text": "25", "start": 224, "end": 226, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.59"}]}, {"sentence": "In addition, Russian forces destroyed five electronic warfare and counterbattery radar stations and two field ammunition depots of the Ukrainian army over the week, the ministry said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Russian", "start": 13, "end": 20, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "five", "start": 38, "end": 42, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.63"}, {"text": "two", "start": 100, "end": 103, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.50"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 135, "end": 144, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 155, "end": 163, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}]}, {"sentence": "Russia’s Battlegroup West repelled 23 Ukrainian army counterattacks and inflicted more than 2,900 casualties on enemy troops in its area of responsibility over the week, the ministry reported.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.99", "spans": [{"text": "Russia", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.81"}, {"text": "Battlegroup West", "start": 9, "end": 25, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.52"}, {"text": "23", "start": 35, "end": 37, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.57"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 38, "end": 47, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.75"}, {"text": "more than 2,900", "start": 82, "end": 97, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.68"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 160, "end": 168, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.94"}]}, {"sentence": "\"Over the week, Battlegroup West units continued advancing deep into the enemy’s defenses and gained more advantageous positions.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.95", "spans": [{"text": "the week", "start": 6, "end": 14, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.79"}, {"text": "Battlegroup West", "start": 16, "end": 32, "value": "PRODUCT", "score": "0.87", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.77"}]}, {"sentence": "They inflicted casualties on formations of two tank and six mechanized brigades, an assault brigade of the Ukrainian army, two territorial defense brigades and two National Guard brigades.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "two", "start": 43, "end": 46, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.72"}, {"text": "six", "start": 56, "end": 59, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.66"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 107, "end": 116, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.77"}, {"text": "two", "start": 123, "end": 126, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.72"}, {"text": "two", "start": 160, "end": 163, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.72"}, {"text": "National Guard", "start": 164, "end": 178, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.74"}]}, {"sentence": "They repelled 23 counterattacks by assault groups of the Ukrainian army,\" the ministry said.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.58", "spans": [{"text": "23", "start": 14, "end": 16, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.60"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 57, "end": 66, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.76"}]}, {"sentence": "The Ukrainian army’s losses in that frontline area over the week amounted to 2,920 personnel, two tanks, 16 other armored combat vehicles, among them eight US-made M113 armored personnel carriers, 46 motor vehicles and 35 field artillery guns, including 11 NATO-supplied 155mm self-propelled artillery systems and howitzers, it specified.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 4, "end": 13, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.61"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 56, "end": 64, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.79"}, {"text": "2,920", "start": 77, "end": 82, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.63"}, {"text": "two", "start": 94, "end": 97, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.55"}, {"text": "16", "start": 105, "end": 107, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.60"}, {"text": "eight", "start": 150, "end": 155, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.55"}, {"text": "US-made", "start": 156, "end": 163, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.55"}, {"text": "M113", "start": 164, "end": 168, "value": "PRODUCT", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.57"}, {"text": "46", "start": 197, "end": 199, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.63"}, {"text": "35", "start": 219, "end": 221, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.59"}, {"text": "11", "start": 254, "end": 256, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.61"}, {"text": "NATO-supplied", "start": 257, "end": 270, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "155mm", "start": 271, "end": 276, "value": "QUANTITY", "score": "0.85", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.61"}]}, {"sentence": "In addition, Russian forces destroyed 13 electronic warfare and counterbattery radar stations and 22 field ammunition depots of the Ukrainian army over the week, the ministry said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Russian", "start": 13, "end": 20, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "13", "start": 38, "end": 40, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.71"}, {"text": "22", "start": 98, "end": 100, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.52"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 132, "end": 141, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 152, "end": 160, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}]}, {"sentence": "Russia’s Battlegroup South liberated three communities in the Donetsk People’s Republic over the week, the ministry reported.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.85", "spans": [{"text": "Russia", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "Battlegroup South", "start": 9, "end": 26, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.75"}, {"text": "three", "start": 37, "end": 42, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.82"}, {"text": "the Donetsk People’s Republic", "start": 58, "end": 87, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 93, "end": 101, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}]}, {"sentence": "\"Battlegroup South units liberated the settlements of Zhelannoye Vtoroye and Ostrovskoye in the Donetsk People’s Republic as a result of decisive operations,\" the ministry said.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.94", "spans": [{"text": "Battlegroup South", "start": 1, "end": 18, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.79"}, {"text": "Zhelannoye Vtoroye", "start": 54, "end": 72, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.84"}, {"text": "Ostrovskoye", "start": 77, "end": 88, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.83"}, {"text": "the Donetsk People’s Republic", "start": 92, "end": 121, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.87"}]}, {"sentence": "Russia’s Defense Ministry reported on October 8 that Battlegroup South units had liberated the settlement of Zoryanoye Pervoye in the Donetsk People’s Republic.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.62", "spans": [{"text": "Russia", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "Defense Ministry", "start": 9, "end": 25, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "October 8", "start": 38, "end": 47, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}, {"text": "Battlegroup South", "start": 53, "end": 70, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.48"}, {"text": "Zoryanoye Pervoye", "start": 109, "end": 126, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}, {"text": "the Donetsk People’s Republic", "start": 130, "end": 159, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.97"}]}, {"sentence": "Over the week, Battlegroup South units inflicted damage on manpower and military hardware of five mechanized brigades, a motorized infantry brigade, two infantry brigades, an assault brigade, a mountain assault brigade, an air assault brigade and two airmobile brigades of the Ukrainian army, a territorial defense brigade and two National Guard brigades.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "the week", "start": 5, "end": 13, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.87"}, {"text": "Battlegroup South", "start": 15, "end": 32, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.70"}, {"text": "five", "start": 93, "end": 97, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.49"}, {"text": "two", "start": 149, "end": 152, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "two", "start": 247, "end": 250, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 277, "end": 286, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.68"}, {"text": "two", "start": 327, "end": 330, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "National Guard", "start": 331, "end": 345, "value": "ORG", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.71"}]}, {"sentence": "They repelled 22 counterattacks by Ukrainian assault groups, it specified.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.58", "spans": [{"text": "22", "start": 14, "end": 16, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.66"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 35, "end": 44, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.64"}]}, {"sentence": "The Ukrainian army’s losses in that frontline area over the week amounted to 4,790 personnel, four armored combat vehicles, 53 motor vehicles and 45 field artillery guns, among them 37 Western-made weapons, it said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 4, "end": 13, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.61"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 56, "end": 64, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.83"}, {"text": "4,790", "start": 77, "end": 82, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.56"}, {"text": "four", "start": 94, "end": 98, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.49"}, {"text": "53", "start": 124, "end": 126, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.50"}, {"text": "45", "start": 146, "end": 148, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.53"}, {"text": "37", "start": 182, "end": 184, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.69"}]}, {"sentence": "In addition, Russian forces destroyed five electronic warfare stations and 10 field ammunition depots of the Ukrainian army over the week, the ministry said.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "Russian", "start": 13, "end": 20, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.96"}, {"text": "five", "start": 38, "end": 42, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.65"}, {"text": "10", "start": 75, "end": 77, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.56"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 109, "end": 118, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.89"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 129, "end": 137, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}]}, {"sentence": "Russia’s Battlegroup Center liberated the settlement of Grodovka in the Donetsk People’s Republic, repulsed 58 Ukrainian counterattacks and inflicted roughly 3,370 casualties on enemy troops in its area of responsibility over the week, the ministry reported.", "tag": "negative", "score": "0.53", "spans": [{"text": "Russia", "start": 0, "end": 6, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.55"}, {"text": "Battlegroup Center", "start": 9, "end": 27, "value": "FAC", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.71"}, {"text": "Grodovka", "start": 56, "end": 64, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.88"}, {"text": "the Donetsk People’s Republic", "start": 68, "end": 97, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}, {"text": "58", "start": 108, "end": 110, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.64"}, {"text": "Ukrainian", "start": 111, "end": 120, "value": "NORP", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "negative", "probability": "0.62"}, {"text": "roughly 3,370", "start": 150, "end": 163, "value": "CARDINAL", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.65"}, {"text": "the week", "start": 226, "end": 234, "value": "DATE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.93"}]}, {"sentence": "\"Battlegroup Center units liberated the settlement of Grodovka in the Donetsk People’s Republic in active operations.", "tag": "positive", "score": "0.95", "spans": [{"text": "Battlegroup Center", "start": 1, "end": 19, "value": "FAC", "score": "0.99", "sentiment": "positive", "probability": "0.72"}, {"text": "Grodovka", "start": 54, "end": 62, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.94"}, {"text": "the Donetsk People’s Republic", "start": 66, "end": 95, "value": "GPE", "score": "1.00", "sentiment": "neutral", "probability": "0.95"}]}, {"sentence": "They inflicted casualties on formations of a tank brigade, seven mechanized brigades, a motorized infantry brigade, two infantry brigades, a jaeger brigade, an airborne brigade of the Ukrainian army, two marine infantry brigades, three territorial defense brigades and three National Guard brigades.", "tag": "negative", "score": "1.00", "spans": [{"text": "seven", "start": 59, "end": 64, "value": "CARDI